Now that we have gone through what is natural language processing, let's look at some of the AWS
services in the area of NLP. So the first one is Amazon Poly. Amazon Poly turns text into
life like speech using deep learning. So what it simply means is that you provided a text file
and it's going to convert that into a audio file. Now let's see how that works. So you have the
Amazon Poly service from AWS. So you feed it some input text. It can be either informed of some
e-learning lectures or an online RSS feed from a blog or news. So you feed these files into Amazon
Poly and it's going to convert it into speech. Okay now let's quickly take a look at some of the
use cases for Poly. So the first one is e-learning. Say you have text-based notes or lectures and you
want to give an option to students to either read through the notes or also listen to the notes.
So that's where you can use Poly to convert text-based notes to audio notes. Second one is content
creation. Say you have an RSS feed from some blog or as I said news. Then you can also provide
the users an option to listen to that feed and not just read it. And then finally it can also be
used in the call center or customer center. Now let's go ahead and check out Amazon Poly from the
console. Now I'm on the AWS console so let me just search for Poly and you can see here Amazon
Poly. So I'm on the home screen of Amazon Poly and you can see here turns text into
lifelike speech using deep learning. So let me just click on try Poly and here it gives you various
options. So do you want generative? So it produces the most expressive and adaptive speech using
generative yet. Then the long form it produces the most natural sounding speech for longer content
neural and standard. So you have the option of selecting one out of the four. So let me just select
neural and next you have to provide the language of the text. So you can see it supports a large
number of languages or the language that it supports are shown here. Then you need to select
the voice. So it will be converted from text to voice. So whether you want a female voice,
a male voice and there's some variation in these different names and you can you can try it out.
So here now I have this in put text. Hi, my name is Ruth. I will read text. You type here.
So I'll just change this text to something else. So I'll just say hi. Welcome to my
Udemy course and then I can just click on listen. Hi, welcome to my Udemy course.
Now if we can just go to this page from AWS on Amazon Poly and here you can see three different
use cases on how you can use poly. So the first one is content creation and you have an RSS
feed and news article is published on the RSS channel and when this new article is published,
it triggers a Lambda function and then this AWS Lambda function retrieves this data from the
feed sends it to the poly, poly transforms the text to speech and uploads the file in the S3 bucket.
So that's one of the use case scenarios on how you can use poly with AWS Lambda and S3.
The next one is the e-learning. So it's very similar. So you upload the new content or lesson
that you have created and you send this data to poly. Poly will convert this text-based
lectures to speech and upload it on the S3 bucket. Then you can use DynamoDB to index all the
lectures with some metadata like what is the name of the lecture, what does it focus on and so on.
And if you have global users, then you can additionally use Amazon CloudFront to access
the files in the S3 bucket which will reduce the latency for global users.
Okay, hopefully we'll clear with Amazon Poly now. I'll see you in the next lecture. Thank you.